The Funk Don't Quit
Get on Up is a drama, music, history film directed by Tate Taylor.
A chronicle of James Brown's rise from extreme poverty to become
one of the most influential musicians in history.
James Brown, played by Chadwick Boseman.
Bobby Byrd, played by Nelsan Ellis.
Ben Bart, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Susie Brown, played by Viola Davis.
Joe Brown, played by Lennie James.
Syd Nathan, played by Fred Melamed.
Get On Up is a 2014 American biographical musical film directed by Tate
Taylor and written by Jez and John-Henry Butterworth.
Produced by Brian Grazer, Mick Jagger, and Taylor and Victoria Pearman, the film stars an ensemble cast featuring Chadwick Boseman as singer James Brown,
Nelsan Ellis as Bobby Byrd, Dan Aykroyd as Ben Bart, Viola Davis as Susie Brown, Craig Robinson as Maceo Parker, and Octavia Spencer as Aunt Honey.
Using a nonlinear narrative, it follows James's stream of consciousness as he recalls events from his life
in an asynchronous manner, occasionally breaking the fourth wall to address the audience.
The project was announced August 2013, along with
Boseman, Davis, Spencer and Ellis' casting.
Principal photography began that November and took place in Mississippi,
where the entire film was shot on location in 49 days.
Get On Up was released on August 1, 2014, in the United States and received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise directed at
the performances of the cast (particularly those of Boseman and Ellis), and grossed $33 million worldwide at the box office.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, 1970s,
biography, south carolina, singer.
The tone is emotional.